# ANUJ AWASTHI

GG Mansion, Jagdish Nagar, Bangalore, Karnataka, 560075 · (790)-564-2483 awasthianuj95@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/awasthianuj95/

Quality-oriented professional with 4 years of experience in Informatica, with sound skills for debugging, customer communication and application development. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the Software Engineer role.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# JUNE 2018 - MARCH 2020

## **TRAINEE**, INFORMATICA

- Joined Informatica After my graduation in 2018 and worked closely with the Advance Product Specialist (APS) team directly.
- Worked as the L3 support engineer/trainee and focused on most complex issues that were raised by L2 support engineers.

#### **MARCH 2020 – OCTOBER 2021**

## ASSOCIATE PRODUCT SPECIALIST, INFORMATICA

- Continued to work as the APS team and collaborated closely with support engineers (L2), R&D and customers.
- Grasped more troubleshooting and debugging skills also developed multiple tools and projects to reduce the workload of the L2/L3 engineers.
- Presented many internal KTs to share my learnings with others.

### **OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT**

## **PRODUCT SPECIALIST, INFORMATICA**

- Currently working as the Product Specialist (L3) for Data quality and slowly progressing towards Cloud Data profiling in Informatica.
- Actively handling many escalations and continuing to build more support tools to help internal team and hence the customers.
- Documented over 100 knowledge based articles (both public and private), whitepapers and delivered over 10 Global brown bag sessions within Informatica and with customers via Ask-an-expert sessions.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **JUNE 2018**

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAHARANA PRATAAP COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING**

• Complete my B.tech in 2018 with 78.7%.

#### **JUNE 2014**

# INTERMEDIATE, CHACHA NEHRU SMARAK INTER COLLEGE,

Completed my Intermediate with 88% and High School with 72.8%

# **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: Java, Python, JS
- Operating Systems: Unix, Windows
- Frameworks: Spring, MVC, Bootstrap
- Tools: Eclipse MAT, Process Monitor, Jstacks, Wireshark, Perforce, GIT, Maven, Salesforce
- Database and more: Oracle, MS SQL Server, MySQL, AWS S3, RedShift, Solr

# PROJECTS AND TOOLS

## **UNIVERSAL STATS COLLECTION UTILITY, JAVA**

- Developed a **Java** based utility which can collect Java stacks (jstacks) as well as Native stacks (Pstack) and other statistics on Unix or Windows environment.
- It can collect simultaneous stats on multiple processes in a single run, which makes it ideal tool for stack analysis in **Multi-Service Architecture** based products.
- An easy-to-use properties file can be used to work it Silent mode, as well as a CLI version for Interactive mode.
- Currently this tool is used by Informatica support engineers and is shipped as part of the product itself.

# **INSTRUMENTATION RESPOSITORY**, JAVA SPRING BOOTSTRAP

- Developed a **web-based** tool which hosts an online repository for all Instrumentations done for a particular scenario.
- This uses a **Solr** based search system which makes it very fast as compared to traditional DBMS.
- Spring MVC + Solr are used in the backend and Bootstrap4, HTML for the front end.
- Provides User login to make sure that the data inside the repository is only modified by it's owner but available for everyone.

## ADDITIONAL SCRIPTS/TOOLS FOR TASK AUTOMATION

- Wrote multiple shell and bat scripts to automate some tasks. Such as scripts to automat the CLI
  commands processing based on customer's use case. Or to automate the task for extracting the
  core stack from a core file using GDB.
- Also contributed to multiple stand-alone programs which were tailored after the internal services to mimic and replicate the issues outside product such as SMTP clients, Adapter client programs etc.
- Currently working on **enhancing** some existing tools (such as custom heapdump parser, instrumentation agent etc) and adding more features.

I have been given an opportunity to learn a greater deal with a specialized team which has always kept me engaged with more complex and detailed issues than the usual and has helped a lot with my learning curve.

I do hereby declare that the above information given by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Anuj Awasthi Dated: June 14, 2022